# **JASON HAYES**

# Software QA Engineer

707 363 0788

jason\_hayes@mac.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ jasonfhayes

Santa Clara, CA 95050

# **Summary:**

Proven software QA engineer with extensive experience and passion for digital media applications and platforms. Highly accomplished black box tester with a track record in bug isolation. Fourteen years of QA background with hands on experience using Python and SQL to write test automation for macOS and iOS.

Extensive working knowledge of Apple and Adobe photo and video applications including Final Cut Pro, Photos, Aperture, Photos, Motion, Photoshop, and Illustrator.

# **Professional Experience:**

## Sr. Software QA Engineer - Apple Inc. | Cupertino, CA

2015 - 2019

Performed QA testing for the Photos app focusing on synchronization of data between devices, volume management, and import/export of data.

- Developed and ran test plans for PTP data sync from Mac to iOS devices.
- Ran performance tests to determine what iOS devices would support RAW decode.
- Ran and triaged daily quicklooks for sync, volume management, and backup.
- Performed weekly image capture presubmission testing for iOS Camera app.

# Software QA Engineer - Apple Inc. | Cupertino, CA

2013-2015

Developed and ran test plans for the ProKit UI framework. Performed manual UI testing testing for Photos 1.0. Ran tests on upgrade scenarios from iPhoto and Aperture.

- Top 5% of bug filers for Photos 1.0 resulting in hundreds of software changes.
- Developed methods for testing memory usage and benchmarking for Photos.
- Ran backup rebuild and restore testing leading up to Photos 2.0 release.

#### Creative/Software Instructor – Apple Inc. | Santa Clara, CA 2006—2013

Worked in the Apple Retail store as a software instructor. Held certifications as an instructor for Final Cut Pro, Motion, and Aperture. Developed a deep understanding of challenges users faced interacting with the software, and supported them in learning how to maximize their user experience.

# Additional Relevant Experience:

Event Photographer/Videographer – Passion Art Photography Inc.

#### **Technical Skills:**

- Scripting experience with Python and Apple's RaftCode UI scripting environment.
- Strong experience using SQL for database query and manipulation.
- Exceptional black box testing experience on desktop and mobile.
- 7+ years of QA experience working on the Photos application for macOS and iOS.
- Used Photoshop and Illustrator personally and professionally for over 15 years.

# **Education:**

# University of California Santa Cruz | Santa Cruz, CA

Certificate in Computer Programming – In progress

# San Jose State University | San Jose, CA

Completed Coursework in Graphic Design and Photography